All right, so now we know we need to be documenting our own projects.
حسنًا، إننا نعرف حتى الآن أنه يجب علينا توثيق المشروعات الخاصة بنا.
But all the documentation we've looked at so far is pretty intense.
ولكن جميع الوثائق التي اطلعنا عليها حتى الآن صعبة للغاية.
In fact, for
في الواقع، يكون نوع
a small personal project, the type of documentation is often overkill.
الوثائق، بالنسبة إلى مشروع شخصي صغير، مبالغ فيه غالبًا.
It would be like writing a cook book when all you need is a single recipe.
وسيبدو مثل كتابة كتاب عن الطهي في حين أن كل ما تحتاج إليه هو وصفة واحدة.
Luckily, there's a type of documentation that lends itself well to small
لحسن الحظ، يوجد نوع من الوثائق يتناسب بشكل جيد مع المشروعات
projects, known as a readme file.
الصغيرة، يسمى الملف التمهيدي.
A readme file's a convention that's existed since back when computer
ويرجع وجود مصطلح الملف التمهيدي إلى الوقت الذي كانت تُكتب فيه
programs were written with punch cards.
برامج الكمبيوتر بواسطة بطاقات مثقبة.
This single file contains relevant information
ويحتوي هذا الملف الفردي على معلومات متعلقة
about the other files in a project's directory.
بالملفات الأخرى الموجودة في دليل مشروع ما.
Readmes are so common that you may have encountered one
تمتاز الملفات التمهيدية بأنها شائعة جدًا لدرجة أنكم ربما تكونوا قد صادفتم ملفًا تمهيديًا
of your own in the past when installing something on your computer.
خاصًا بكم قبل ذلك عند تثبيت شيء ما على جهاز الكمبيوتر لديكم.
Its name exists, usually written in all caps to stand out in a directory so
وعادةً يوجد اسمه مكتوبًا بالكامل بأحرف كبيرة ليكون ظاهرًا في الدليل
that users would be more likely to read it.
حتى تزيد احتمالية قراءة المستخدمين له.
Check it out for yourself.
فتحققوا من ذلك بأنفسكم.
I've included a link to three different readmes in the instructor notes.
لقد قمتُ بتضمين رابط لثلاثة ملفات تمهيدية مختلفة في ملاحظات المعلم.
As you examine them,
فحين تفحصونها،
think to yourself, what information is being communicated in this file?
فكروا مع أنفسكم بشأن، ما المعلومات التي يتم توصيلها في هذا الملف؟
And how is this information being structured?
وكيف يتم تنظيم هذه المعلومات؟
And do you notice any patterns across these readmes?
وهل لاحظتم أي أنماط عبر هذه الملفات التمهيدية؟